Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we're
going to the gym today, right Marco?
That's right today. We're
going to go to the gym and
we're going to try to lose
weight or to get in shape.
So before we start out though, there is a
phrasal verb that we should take a look at.
So today in vocabulary
preview we're looking
at this phrase to work
out or working out.
That's right. So when we go to the gym,
this is what we do. We go there to work out.
To exercise or to tone up,
this is just a way of saying that
I'm going to go somewhere
like a gym to exercise myself.
That's right. So with that in mind, we're
going to go to the gym. We're going to work
out and we're going to learn a lot of words
today about what exactly goes on in the gym.
Do you want to go catch a movie tonight?
I can't. I have to go to the gym. Come on.
You can go tomorrow. Just skip it today.
It's not as if you're
going to get in trouble.
Actually, I will. I'm
working out with a personal
trainer that gets on
my case if I don't go.
I like it because it makes me feel
more obligated to go and get healthy.
That's cool. Does your personal trainer
basically teach you how to work out?
Yeah. He makes a workout
plan depending on the areas
I want to work on or the
muscles I want to build.
Like, for example, in order to get better
muscle tone in my abs, pecs and biceps,
he makes me work
out with free weights.
Then for my quads, calves and
hamstrings, I do leg lifts or squats.
Sounds like you're
really getting into shape.
All right. So now we're back.
Let's take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right. First of all, in
today's dialogue, we heard
a lot about this person
called a personal trainer.
What does a personal trainer do, Marco?
So basically, you have
a person that is your
coach, the person that
guides you and teaches
you how to work out
or what you should do.
All right. So personal means it's just
for me. This person is only helping me.
And a trainer is someone who,
like you said, gives me guidance.
So personal trainer is
someone who will work with
me every day or maybe
one time a week to really
get the most out of my workout.
That's right. So that
is a personal trainer.
And as we said, he's going
to help us to build muscle.
We want to build muscle
when we go to the gym.
All right. So this is an
interesting one because
the verb is not to grow or
to make the verb is to build.
So I have muscles, but I
want my muscles to get bigger.
So I go to build
muscles at the gym.
That's right. You might even
hear this phrase, a body builder.
So this idea that you make them.
Yeah, exactly. So you,
you don't get muscle.
You don't create muscle.
You build a muscle.
And alongside with muscles, not only do you
get them big, but you also get muscle tone.
All right. So muscle tone
basically means definition.
So maybe before
you start to work out,
your body is very soft.
You can't see the muscles.
Well, when you start
to see those muscles,
you see the lines in
your body, your skin gets
tighter, not so soft.
That's called muscle tone.
That's right. So then you can see
the muscles. That's muscle tone.
And now the muscles
that we most commonly go
to the gym to work out, we're
going to name really quickly.
And we're going to
see where they are.
So the first one that
we mentioned were abs.
Okay. This is an important one,
especially if you want to go to the beach.
The abs are located on your
stomach. So you see those kind
of rectangles, those
squares on your stomach,
those are the abs. That's right.
And now for guys, also we
want to work out our pecs or
our pictorial muscles.
So those are on your
chest, below your neck,
but above your stomach.
That's right. And another
important one on your
arm, we have our biceps.
All right, men usually
like to show these
off or at least boys do.
These are on your arms.
So you know when you make
that L shape with your arm
and you squeeze like papa.
Those are your biceps.
Those are your biceps, exactly.
And now obviously
going down towards our
legs, now we have our
quad muscles, our quads.
All right. So those are on the
top part of your legs, right, Marco?
Mm-hmm. In front. In front.
So like on the top of your thigh.
Exactly. And now right behind the back
part of your leg, you have your hamstrings.
Hamstring. Now you
hear about this one a lot
because people injure
their hamstrings pretty easily
in football or in
running. Yeah, that's right.
Sometimes if you're
running and you didn't stretch
your muscles in that warm,
you can pull a hamstring.
All right. So that hamstring
is an important one.
But we have one
more. That's right.
We have our calves. And these are
in the bottom right above our feet.
So I don't have any
muscles except for
this one because I ride
my bike. And when you ride
your bike, this gets big.
So your calves are that
part of your leg above
your foot, but below your
knee in the back. That's
right, the back part.
Very good. So all of
these muscles are some of
the most common
ones that we work out.
So now let's move on to some
important phrases on fluency
builder. Do you want to go catch a movie
tonight? I can't. I have to go to the gym.
Come on. You can go
tomorrow. Just skip it today.
It's not as if you're
going to get in trouble.
Actually, I will. I'm
working out with a personal
trainer that gets on
my case if I don't go.
I like it because it makes me feel
more obligated to go and get healthy.
That's cool. Does your personal trainer
basically teach you how to work out? Yeah.
He makes a workout plan
depending on the areas I
want to work on or the
muscles I want to build.
Like, for example, in order to get better
muscle tone in my abs, pecs and biceps,
he makes me work out with free weights.
Then for my quads, calves and hamstrings,
I do leg lifts or squats. Sounds
like you're really getting into shape.
So the beginning of the
dialogue, the friends were
trying to decide what
to do and one friend said,
do you want to go catch
a movie? That's right.
So to catch a movie, do you
want to go catch a movie?
It sounds funny because,
you know, catch means to
hold something in your
hands after someone throws it.
Right. So throw and
catch. But here, it doesn't
mean to actually hold
something in your hands.
It means, do you want
to go see a movie? Right.
Exactly. So it's a very
informal colloquial way of
saying, hey, do you
want to go to the movies?
Do you want to go
see a movie? Maybe not.
Like, yeah, serious date
or something. Just for fun.
Do you want to go catch
a movie? That's right.
Let's go catch a movie.
All right. So obviously,
we can't go to the movies
because we got to go to the gym.
And we have to go to the gym because
our personal trainer will get on our case.
The personal trainer will
get on my case if I don't go.
All right. So someone will get on my case
if I don't do this. So this, this is an
interesting way of saying,
my personal trainer will
criticize me or will be angry
with me if I don't do this.
That's right. So
you can use it with,
for example, your parents,
your parents are always
getting on your case because
you don't clean your room.
Yeah, my mom gets on my case when I don't
tell her where I'm going when I go out.
So that means to
criticize, to give you a hard
time to get angry at you
or even maybe yell at you.
But you can change the
pronoun. So he gets on my
case, but I can get on
your case. That's right.
So just remember that someone
gets on someone else's case.
That's where the person goes.
And of course, if you
want to tell that person to
stop bothering you, you
just say, get off my case.
All right. So he's on
her case. Get off my case.
And that's right. And
now to finish things off,
the whole reason why we're going to
the gym is because we want to get in shape.
All right. Great phrase
here to get in shape.
This is something a lot of
people like to do in the new year.
So they say, okay,
it's a new year.
I want a new body. I'm
going to get in shape.
That means I will lose weight, build
some muscle, and start to feel good.
That's right. So we
want to get in shape.
Very good. Let's listen to
our dialogue one last time.
Do you want to go catch a movie tonight?
I can't. I have to go to the gym.
Come on. You can go
tomorrow. Just skip it today.
It's not as if you're
going to get in trouble.
Actually, I will. I'm
working out with a personal
trainer that gets on
my case if I don't go.
I like it because it makes me feel
more obligated to go and get healthy.
That's cool. Does your personal trainer
basically teach you how to work out?
Yeah. He makes a workout
plan depending on the
areas I want to work on or
the muscles I want to build.
Like, for example, in order to get better
muscle tone in my abs, pecs, and biceps,
he makes me workout with
freeways. Then for my quads,
calves, and hamstrings,
I do leg lifts or squats.
Sounds like you're
really getting into shape.
Alright, so going
to the gym, getting a
personal trainer is a
good idea or a bad idea.
I think for some people who have
a hard time getting motivated, so
people who don't like
to go to the gym, it's
a great idea because
having another person
push you can really help. I think for other
people who are already pushing themselves,
it's not as helpful. I think also if
you just start out going to the gym,
I think you should get a personal
trainer for the first couple of weeks.
Because you really have
to understand and learn
what you're doing in the
purpose of that exercise
and figure out how many
sets, how many repetitions.
All this is very important because
some people just go and they overwork it.
They do and they don't know
how to use the machines or
the weights and you
can actually harm yourself.
You can pull a hamstring or something
if you don't know what you're doing.
So for people who've never
learned how to exercise,
maybe it's a good idea like you say. Well,
it's a very interesting thing actually
gyms as well, very popular nowadays,
especially with the holidays passing,
you know, people gain
some holiday weight.
You got to go back to
the gym to lose that weight.
That's right. So let us
know. Do you go to the gym?
If so, what parts of your
body do you like to focus on?
Our website is EnglishPod.com. All
right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]